Guide to the Roland Park Company Records, ca. 1891-1962
Roland Park Company Records, ca. 1891-1962
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous (T-Z), 1917 (Box 112)
  - Harwood personal, 1917 (Box 112)
  - G.J. Smith, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Annexation, 1915 and 1917 (Box 112)
  - Letters (1-279), 1918 (Box 113)
  - Letters (280-699), 1918 (Box 114)
  - Letters (700-999) Miscellaneous A-B, 1918 (Box 115)
  - Miscellaneous (C-H), 1918 (Box 116)
  - Miscellaneous (I-P), 1918 (Box 117)
  - Miscellaneous (Q-Z), 1918 (Box 118)
  - Bouton personal, 1918 (Box 119)
  - Harwood personal, 1918 (Box 119)
  - Letters (1-448), 1919 (Box 120)
  - Letters (449-999), 1919 (Box 121)
  - Miscellaneous (A-G), 1919 (Box 122)
  - Miscellaneous (H-M), 1919 (Box 123)
  - Miscellaneous (N-V), 1919 (Box 124)
  - Miscellaneous (W-Z), 1919 (Box 125)
  - Bouton personal, 1919 (Box 125)
  - Harwood personal, 1919 (Box 125)
  - Smith Estate, 1918-1919 (Box 125)
  - Letters (1-997), 1920 (Box 126)
  - Miscellaneous (A-K), 1920 (Box 127)
  - Miscellaneous (L-We), 1920 (Box 128)
  - Miscellaneous (We-Z), 1920 (Box 129)
  - Bouton personal, 1920 (Box 129)
  - Harwood personal, 1920-1921 (Box 129)
  - Smith Estate, 1920 (Box 129)
  - Letters (1-970), 1921 (Box 130)
  - Miscellaneous (A-G), 1921 (Box 131)
  - Miscellaneous (H-R), 1921 (Box 132)
  - Miscellaneous (S-Z), 1921 (Box 133)
  - Bouton personal, 1921 (Box 133)
  - Engineering Department, 1921-1922 (Box 134)
  - Letters (1-970), 1922 (Box 135)
  - Letters (Miscellanous A-H), 1922 (Box 136)
  - Letters (Miscellaneous I-Ste), 1922 (Box 137)
  - Letters (Miscellaneous Str-Z), 1922 (Box 138)
  - J.N. Hering, Purchasing Agent, 1920-1922 (Box 138)
  - Bouton personal, 1920-1924 (Box 138)
  - Letters (1-999), 1923 (Box 139)
  - Miscellaneous (A-J), 1923 (Box 140)
  - Letters (Miscellaneous K-Z), 1923 (Box 141)
  - Eng. Division Con. Elec.Co., 1923 (Box 142)
  - Letters (1-998), 1924 (Box 143)
  - Letters (Miscellaneous A-G), 1924 (Box 144)
  - Letters (Miscellaneous H-P), 1924 (Box 145)
  - Letters (Miscellaneous Q-Z), 1924 (Box 146)
  - Engr. Dept. Correspondence, 1924 (Box 147)
  - Cons. S.E. Power Co., 1921-1924 (Box 147)
  - Harwood Correspondence, 1921-1924 (Box 147)
  - Company Business-City Correspondence, 1920-1924 (Box 148)
  - Letters (1-1000), 1925 (Box 149)
  - Miscellaneous (A-H), 1925 (Box 150)
  - Miscellaneous (I-Sa), 1925 (Box 151)
  - Miscellaneous (Sc-Z), 1925 (Box 152)
  - Homeland, 1925 (Box 152)
  - Homeland, 1925 (Box 153)
  - Co. Business Homeland and Guilford, 1925 (Box 153)
  - Letters (1-1000), 1926 (Box 154)
  - Miscellaneous (A-Gh), 1926 (Box 155)
  - Miscellaneous (Gn-O), 1926 (Box 156)
  - Miscellaneous (P-Z), 1926 (Box 157)
  - Company Business, 1926 (Box 158)
  - Homeland, 1926 (Box 158)
  - Bouton and Harwood, 1925-1926 (Box 158)
  - Letters (1-1000), 1927 (Box 159)
  - Miscellaneous (A-G), 1927 (Box 160)
  - Miscellaneous (H-O), 1927 (Box 161)
  - Miscellaneous (P-Z), 1927 (Box 162)
  - Company Business (A-Z), 1927 (Box 163)
  - Homeland Letters (A-Z), 1927 (Box 163)
  - Letters (1-659), 1928 (Box 164)
  - Letters (660-1000), 1928 (Box 165)
  - Miscellaneous (A-Ha), 1928 (Box 166)
  - Miscellaneous (He-R), 1928 (Box 167)
  - Company Business, 1928 (Box 169)
  - Bouton letters, 1927-1928 (Box 169)
  - Homeland Letters, 1928 (Box 169)
  - Letters (1-661), 1929 (Box 170)
  - Letters (662-970), 1929 (Box 171)
  - City Correspondence File #882, 1925-1933 (Box 172)
  - Miscellaneous (A-L), 1929 (Box 173)
  - Miscellaneous (Mc-Z), 1929 (Box 174)
  - Company Business, City Correspondence, 1929 (Box 175)
  - Homeland Co. Business (2 series), 1929 (Box 175)
  - Letters (1-717), 1929 (Box 176)
  - Letters (718-922), 1930 (Box 177)
  - Miscellaneous (A-K), 1930 (Box 178)
  - Miscellaneous (L-Z), 1930 (Box 179)
  - Letters (732-1000), 1931 (Box 181)
  - Miscellaneous (A-M), 1931 (Box 182)
  - Miscellaneous (N-Z), 1931 (Box 183)
  - General correspondence, 1931 (Box 184)
  - Bouton and others, 1931 (Box 184)
  - Letters (1-1000), 1932 (Box 185)
  - Miscellaneous (A-Mc), 1932 (Box 186)
  - Miscellaneous (M-Z), 1932 (Box 187)
  - Mowbray, 1930-1932 (Box 188)
  - General (A-S), 1932 (Box 188)
  - Interoffice correspondence File #80, 1932 (Box 188)
  - Letters (1-1000), 1933 (Box 189)
  - Miscellaneous (A-L), 1933 (Box 190)
  - Miscellaneous (M-Z), 1933 (Box 191)
  - General Correspondence, 1933 (Box 192)
  - Mowbray Personal, 1933 (Box 192)
  - Interoffice, 1933 (Box 192)
  - Letters (1-964), 1934 (Box 193)
  - Miscellaneous (A-Mc), 1934 (Box 194)
  - Miscellaneous (M-Z), 1934 (Box 195)
  - General Correspondence, 1934 (Box 196)
  - Interoffice (Sales), 1934 (Box 196)
  - Company Business, 1934 (Box 197)
  - Letters (1-963), 1934 (Box 198)
  - Miscellaneous (A-G), 1934 (Box 198)
  - Miscellaneous (H-Z), 1935 (Box 199)
  - General Correspondence, 1935 (Box 200)
  - Company Business, 1935 (Box 200)
  - Sec. Correspondence, 1935 (Box 201)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1935 (Box 201)
  - Engr. Dept., 1935 (Box 202)
  - Map List, 1935 (Box 202)
  - Miscellaneous Publications, 1935 (Box 202)
  - Sales Dept., Southerland Correspondence
    - Reminders, 1918-1919 (Box 203)
    - Reminders, 1920 (Box 203)
    - Reminders, 1921 (Box 204)
    - A-Z Correspondence, 1921 (Box 204)
    - A-Z Correspondence, 1922 (Box 205)
    - Reminders, 1922 (Box 205)
    - A-Z Correspondence, 1923 (Box 206)
    - Reminders, 1923 (Box 206)
    - A-Z Correspondence, 1924 (Box 207)
    - Reminders, 1924 (Box 207)
    - A-Z Correspondence, 1925 (Box 208)
    - Reminders, 1925 (Box 208)
    - A-G, L-R, R-Z Correspondence, 1926 (Box 209)
    - Holiday Personal, 1926 (Box 209)
    - Haskell Personal, 1926 (Box 209)
    - Exhibition Houses, 1926 (Box 209)
    - Advertising, 1926 (Box 209)
    - Architectural Commission Reports, 1929 (Box 209)
    - A-Z Personal, 1927 (Box 210)
    - Holiday Personal, 1927 (Box 210)
    - A-Z Correspodence, 1928 (Box 211)
    - A-Z Correspondence, 1928 (Box 212)
    - Bouton, Harwood, Dix, Simmons Correspondence, 1925 (Box 213)
    - Bouton, Harwood, Dix, Simmons Correspondence, 1927 (Box 213)
    - Bouton, Harwood, Dix, Simmons Correspondence, 1929-1930 (Box 213)
  - Mowbray, General Correspondence
    - Correspondence (A-M), 1935-1938 (Box 214)
    - Correspondence (N-Z), 1938 (Box 215)
    - Correspondence (A-M), 1939-1942 (Box 215)
    - Correspondence (O-Z), 1941 (Box 216)
    - Correspondence (A-Z), 1943 (Box 216)
  - Advisory Committee on Finance
    - Commission on Government Efficiency and Economics, 1935-193 (Box 217)
    - Commission on Government Efficiency and Economics, 1941 (Box 217)
    - Housing #1 (Box 217)
    - Housing #2 (Box 217)
  - N.A.R.E.B.
    - N.A.R.E.B., 1938 (Box 218)
    - N.A.R.E.B. Correspondence, 1939 (Box 218)
    - D. and H.B. Division Housing Committee (Box 218)
    - N.A.R.E.B. 1939 Meetings (Box 218)
    - N.A.R.E.B. Miscellaneous, 1940-1941 (Box 218)
    - N.A.R.E.B. L.O. and H.B. Division, 1940 (Box 218)
  - Waverly Rehabilitation Survey Program
    - Waverly Rehabilitation Survey Program; Chamber of Commerce of the United States (Box 219)
  - Letters and Correspondence
    - Letters (1-970), 1936 (Box 220)
    - Company Business (A-C, H-Z), 1936 (Box 220)
    - Miscellaneous (A-Z), 1936 (Box 221)
    - Letters (1-964), 1937 (Box 222)
    - Miscellaneous Letters (Box 223)
    - Letters (A-Mc), 1937 (Box 223)
    - Letters (Ma-Z), 1937 (Box 224)
    - Letters (1-963), 1938 (Box 225)
    - Letters (A-L), 1938 (Box 226)
    - Letters (M-Z), 1938 (Box 227)
    - Letters (A-Mc), 1939 (Box 228)
    - Letters (1-970), 1936 (Box 220)
    - Letters (A-Mc), 1939 (Box 229)
    - Letters (Ma-Z), 1939 (Box 230)
    - Letters (A-Mc), 1940 (Box 231)
    - Letters (Ma-Z), 1940 (Box 232)
    - Correspondence (A-Mi), 1941 (Box 233)
    - Correspondence (Mo-Z), 1941 (Box 234)
    - Correspondence (A-M), 1942 (Box 235)
    - Correspondence (N-Z), 1942 (Box 236)
    - Correspondence (A-Mc), 1943 (Box 237)
    - Correspondence (M-Z), 1943 (Box 238)
    - Correspondence (A-Z), 1944 (Box 239)
    - Correspondence (A-L), 1945 (Box 240)
    - Correspondence (M-Z), 1945 (Box 241)
    - Correspondence (A-L), 1946 (Box 242)
    - Correspondence (M-Z), 1946 (Box 243)
    - Letters (A-Z), 1950 (Box 244)
    - Letters (A-Z), 1951 (Box 245)
- Series II. Miscellaneous Materials
  - Annual Reports (Box 246)
  - "Garden Houses" By Roland Park Co. (Box 246)
  - Letters to Stockholders (Box 246)
  - Architectural Files, 1942-1953 (Box 246)
  - Articles of Incorperation (Box 246)
  - Indentures (Box 246)
  - N.A.R.E.B. "Newsletter" (Box 246)
  - Architecural Reports, 1926-1930, 1930-1939 (Box 246)
  - Architectural Approval Recrods for Orchards, 1962 (Box 247)
  - Northwood Apartments; Balance Sheets, Profit and Loss Statement (Box 248)
  - Northwood Shopping Center, Personal Property Tax and Franchise Tax Reports and Federal Tax Returns, 1944 (Box 248)
  - Annual meetings of the stockholders: certified lists of stockholders, proxies and other papers related to the meetings, 1942-1954 (Box 248)
  - Copies of Articles of Merger (July 31, 1951) and Articles of Incorpoperation (Box 248)
  - Balance sheets and statement of profit and loss (Box 248)
  - Roland Park Co: Income Tax Returns, 1945-1954 (Box 249)
  - Roland Park Co: Profit and Loss Statements, 1920-1949 (Box 249)
  - Roland Park Co: Statements, 1941-1950 (Box 249)
  - Copy of Executed Wavier of Restrictions on Assessments and Deficiency in Federal Income Tax (Box 249)
  - Homeland: Fiscal Records and correspondence and assorted reports, 1922-1925 (Box 250)
  - Cumberland Files (Box 251)
  - Gibson Island Files (Box 251)
  - Dunleer Apartment Co., Selected Files (Box 252)
  - George B. Simmons (Vice-President Roland Park Co.), Selected Files relating to the Lock Raven Development and to general company business (Box 252)
  - Roland Park Annual Meetings (Box 253)
  - Profit and Loss Statements (Box 253)
  - Merger and Liquidation papers (Box 253)
  - Architectural Specifications and Standard re Roland Park (Box 253)
  - Income Tax and Land Cost Figures (Box 253)
  - Minutes, Marble Hall Col, Montabello and Swansee Co. (Box 253)
  - Forest Hills Gardents, L.I., miscellaneous files and bulletins of Letchworth and other Garden cities (Box 254)
  - Warsaw, Roland Housing Project, Correspondence concerning (Box 254)
  - Taxes prior to 1921 (Box 254)
  - Roland Park Company
    - Roland Park Deeds, 1904-1920 (Box 255)
    - Minutes of Meetings (Box 256)
    - Articles of Incorporation (Box 256)
    - By-laws (Box 256)
    - Minutes of Board of Directors, 1924-1936 (Box 256)
    - Statements, 1906-1921 (Box 257)
    - Minutes, 1911, 1913, 1924 (Box 258)
  - Miscellaneous files (Box 259)
  - Miscellaneous files including Roland Park Company's statements of profit and loss, 1898, 1905-1908 (Box 260)
  - Auditors Reports, 1910-1916 (Box 260)
  - Roland Park League Files (Box 260)
  - Letchworth pamplets (Box 260)
  - volume entitled "Record of Transfers-Outlying Property (of RP Co.) (Box 261)
  - volume entitled Evergreen, 1899-1952 [1899-1911] (Box 261)
  - volume entitled "Safe-Sales Dept." (articles of incoproration, monthly meetings, board of directors and stockholders), ca. 1891-1903 (Box 261)
  - envelope entitled "Mortgage Assignments 1935" (Homeland) (Box 261)
  - C.K. Wells, Jr., Inc. Houses on lots 79, 80 and 81 Witherspoon Rd., Houses 3001-3003 Williamsburg Group-Homeland, 1928, 1936-1942 (Box 261)
  - Roads and Maintenance, Deed and Agreement, 1909 (Box 261)
  - certificate of incorporation, bylaws, pamphlets and typescripts (Box 261)
  - Executive Committee Minutes (carbons), Aug. 18, 1933-Apr. 12, 1935 (Box 261)
  - Rogers Forge Gold Club, Statements, 1930-1931 (Box 261)
  - A paperbound volume of Sutherlan's copies of Executive Committee meetings (incomplete series), 1919-1928 (Box 261)
  - F.E. Wurzbacher Corp.-Homes Lots 1, 2, 31-8, Section 2, Northwood Homes 4001-4010 Argonne Drive (Box 261)
  - Plans and Specifications, Documents-Rugby Road, Guilford, Megrew House, Lot 4, Blk 54 Guilford (Box 261)
  - Northwood Liquidation Inc. Deeds, plans and misellaneous papers (Box 262)
  - Northwood Shopping Center, Inc., 1940's-1950's (Box 262)
  - Unlabeled record of house and lot sales contracts (Roland Park and Guilford), 1913-1914, 1922-1924 (Box 262)
  - House and Lot Sales Record No. 2 (Roland Park, Guilford, and south of University Parkway (co. and brokerage sales)), 1920-1926 (Box 262)
  - House and Lot Sales Record No. 3 (Roland Park, Guilford, Evergreen, and Outside of District (brokerage sales: Hurstliegh, Gibson Island, the Orchards)), 1927-1941 (Box 262)
  - Roland Park Homeland Co: Orig. Schedule Sales Prices, ca. 1938 including 1938 Resubdivision of Northwood, Sections 1-4, Guilford, 1940 (Box 262)
  - Mortgage book, 1897-1912 (Box 263)
  - Roland Park Subscription List and stockholders (Box 263)
  - Joppa Road Subdivision, No. 2 Miscellaneous Transfer Book (includes Deed and Restriction booklet, July 1, 1913 which contains restrictions for Guilford) (Box 263)
  - Northwood Realty Co. formerly Pentride Apt. Co., 1947-1949 (Box 263)
  - Northwood Apt. Inc. (includes information concerning financing and eventual acquistion of property by Prudential, 1944-1951 (Box 263)
  - Northwood Shopping Center Inc., acquisition of land (Box 263)
  - Unlabelled record of lot and house sales in all Roland Park Co. properties, 1920's (Box 263)
  - Guilford-record of contracts, deeds, etc., 1920's (Box 263)
  - Deeds and Agreements (1-151) (Box 265)
  - Deeds and Agreements (152-224D) (Box 266)
  - Miscellaneous contracts (1-115) Executed House and Lot Sales Contracts (1-199) (Box 267)
  - Miscellaneous files, letterbook (1920), survery (1937), Reginal Plan Newsletter, ex. comm. minutes (1914), profit and loss statements (Box 268)
  - Maps of Roland Park Homeland Plats (1929), Guilford Estates and other assorted plats (Box 269)
  - Baltimore Company: Minutes, Stockholder proxies, list of stockholders (Box 270)
  - Letter books, 1891-1896 (Box 271)
  - Letter books, 1896-1900 (Box 272)
  - Letter books, 1896-1900 (Box 273)
  - Letter books, 1905-1906 (Box 274)
  - Letter books, 1905-1906 (Box 275)
  - Letter books, 1907-1908 (Box 276)
  - Letter books, 1908-1909 (Box 277)
  - Letter books, 1909-1910 (Box 278)
  - Letter books, 1910 (Box 279)
  - Letter books, 1911 (Box 280)
  - Letter books, 1911-1912 (Box 281)
  - Letter books, 1912-1913 (Box 282)
  - Letter books, 1913-1914 (Box 283)
  - Letter books, 1914-1915 (Box 284)
  - Letter books, 1915-1916 (Box 285)
  - Letter books, 1916-1917 (Box 286)
  - Letter books, 1917-1919 (Box 287)
  - Letter books, 1919-1921 (Box 288)
  - Letter books, 1921-1922 (Box 289)
  - Letter books (Bouton-Personal), 1892-1906 (Box 290)
  - Letter books (Bouton-Personal), 1906-1919 (Box 291)
  - Blueprints (Box 292)
  - Roland Park Magazine (1928-1930), incomplete; Gardens, Houses and People (1931-1932), incomplete; 1933-1945 inclusive (Box 293)
  - Gardens, Houses, and People, 1945-1947; 1949, incomplete; "The Golden Year" (Special 50th Anniversary Issue of Gardens, Houses and People) (Box 294)
  - Newspaper clipping scrapbooks (Box 295)
  - Newspaper clipping scrapbook (Box 296)
  - Asstd. Ledgers (Box 297)
  - Miscellaneous files (Box 298)
  - Company Minutes, 1945-1960 (Box 299)
  - Misc. items including: letter books, 1918-1920, and misc. files and sample fiscal records (Box 300)
  - Annual Meetings of Stockholders: certified lists of stockholders, proxies, other papers related to the meetings, inclusive, 1943-1950 (Box 301)
  - Miscellaneous files and letter books (Box 302)
  - Annual meetings of stockholders; certified lists, etc. (Box 303)
  - Miscellaneous files (Box 304)
  - Miscellaneous files and ledgers (Box 305)
  - Roland Park Company: Beaver Dam, Elk River and Calvert Country-Prince Frederick Shopping Center (Box 306)
  - Miscellaneous files (Box 307)
  - Letters (A-B), 1947 (Box 308)
  - Letters(C-E), 1947 (Box 308)
  - Letters (F-H), 1947 (Box 308)
  - Letters (I-L), 1947 (Box 308)
  - Letters (M), 1947 (Box 308)
  - Letters (N-P), 1947 (Box 308)
  - Letters (R-S), 1947 (Box 309)
  - Letters (T-X), 1947 (Box 309)
  - Letters (A-C), 1948 (Box 309)
  - Letters (D-G), 1948 (Box 309)
  - Letters (H-K), 1948 (Box 309)
  - Letters (L-M), 1948 (Box 309)
  - Letters (N-Q), 1948 (Box 310)
  - Letters (R-S), 1948 (Box 310)
  - Letters (T-Z), 1948 (Box 310)
  - Letters (A-C), 1949 (Box 310)
  - Letters (D-G), 1949 (Box 310)
  - Letters (H-K), 1949 (Box 311)
  - Letters (L-M), 1949 (Box 311)
  - Letters (N-R), 1949 (Box 311)
  - Letters (S-V), 1949 (Box 311)
  - Letters (W-Z), 1949 (Box 311)
  - Sales and statistics, 1920-1953 (Box 312)
  - Hedm's Office, 1920-1953 (Box 312)
  - M.A.R.E.B. Central Atlantic Region, 1944 (Box 312)
  - J.M. Mowbray (Box 312)
  - J.M. Mowbray Real Estate Bd. of Baltimore (Box 312)
  - National Association of Real Estate and Realtors Washington Committee, 1945 (Box 313)
  - J.M. Mowbray R.P. Co. Files (A-N), 1945 (Box 313)
  - J.M. Mowbray R.P. Co. Files (O-Z), 1945 (Box 313)
  - J.M. Mowbray R.P. Co. Files (A-N), 1946 (Box 313)
  - J.M. Mowbray R.P. Co. Files (O-Z), 1946 (Box 313)
  - J.M. Mowbray R.P. Co. Files (A-Na), 1947 (Box 314)
  - J.M. Mowbray R.P. Co. Files (Na-Z), 1947 (Box 314)
  - Interoffice-Mowbray, 1948-1949 (Box 314)
  - Sales Force, 1949-1950 (Box 314)
  - National Association of Real Estate Boards (Box 314)
  - Real Estate Board of Baltimore (Box 314)
  - N.A.R.E.B. aud N.A.H.B. Correspondence, 1949 (Box 314)
  - Real Estate Board of Baltimore and Realtor's Washington Committee Correspondence, 1949 (Box 314)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence (A-R), 1946 (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence (S-Z), 1946 (Box 315)
  - U.L.I. Correspondence (Box 315)
  - Northwood Shopping Center Correspondence and miscellaneous data thru 1950 (A-N) (Box 315)
  - Northwood Shopping Center Correspondence and miscellaneous data thru 1950 (N-Z) (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence (A-K), 1950 (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence, N.A.R.E.B. (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence, N.A.R.E.B. (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence, N.A.R.E.B. (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence, N.A.R.E.B. (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence, N.A.R.E.B. (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence, N.A.R.E.B. (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence, N.A.R.E.B. (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence, N.A.R.E.B. (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence, N.A.R.E.B. (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence, N.A.R.E.B. (Box 315)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence, N.A.R.E.B. (Box 315)
  - Urban Land Institute (L-Z), 1950 (Box 315)
  - Northwood Shopping Center, J.M.M., 1951-1952 (Box 316)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence (A-M), 1951 (Box 316)
  - R.P. Co. Correspondence (N-Z), 1951 (Box 316)
  - N.A.R.E.B. (Box 316)
  - Real Estate Board of Baltimore (Box 316)
  - Northwood Shopping Center, 1955-1956 (Box 316)
  - Northwood Shopping Center Inc. (Box 317)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 317)
  - Hillendale Realty Co. (Box 317)
  - Sales Dept. Statistics (Box 317)
  - Sales Dept. Statistics (Box 317)
  - Exclusive File (Box 318)
  - Northwood and Pentridge Apt. Housess (Box 318)
  - Financial Statements, 1940's (Box 318)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 318)
  - Baltimore Co. (Box 319)
  - Stocks and Stockholders (Box 319)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 320)
  - Stocks and taxes (Box 320)
  - Miscellaneous taxes and stocks (Box 321)
  - Tax Records (Box 321)
  - Tax Records (Box 322)
  - Letter K of Arch. Restrictions for Homeland Journals (Box 323)
  - Northwood Realty and Pentridge Apartments (Box 323)
  - Urban Land Institute and Water Rates Commission (Box 323)
  - Roland Park and Montebello Co. (Box 323)
  - Construction Costs Material (Box 324)
  - Culmon Co. and Roland Park Co. merger (Box 324)
  - Stockholder's Material (Box 324)
  - Rogers Forge Golf Club (Box 324)
  - Roland Park Co. Stockholders meetings (Box 325)
  - Director's meetings, 1928-1942 (Box 325)
  - Roland Park Co. Stockholders meetings and director's meetings, 1928-1942 (Box 326)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 327)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 328)
  - Hillendale Realty Co. (Box 329)
  - Hillendale Realty Co.-Baltimore Co. History (Box 329)
  - Hillendale Realty Co.-Stockholders Lists and meetings (Box 329)
  - Hillendale Realty Co.-Plots (Box 329)
  - Hillendale Realty Co.-Tax Reports (Box 329)
  - Hillendale Realty Co.-Certificates of due and by-laws (Box 329)
  - Hillendale Realty Co.-Mowbray recommendation letters (Box 329)
  - Hillendale Realty Co.-Northwood Apartments and shopping center (Box 329)
  - Merchants Assoc. Papers (Northwood) (Box 330)
  - Hecht Company Plots (Box 330)
  - Eng. Studies and Proposals for Northwood Shopping (Box 330)
  - Goucher Shopping Center Reports (Box 330)
  - Report done by Homer Hoyt Association (Box 330)
  - Roland Park Co. Papers (Box 331)
  - Homeland Co. Papers (Box 331)
  - Guilford Co. Papers (Box 331)
  - Contains two disassembeld photograph albums that were shelved unboxed at the annex. One album contained Homeland Progress photographs; one contained photographs of Dundalk (Box 341)
  - Dundalk, Md. (26 photographs) (Box 341, Folder 1)
  - Dundalk, Md. (26 photographs) (Box 341, Folder 2)
  - Dundalk, Md. (26 photographs) (Box 341, Folder 3)
  - Homeland Progress Photographs (148 photographs) (Box 341, Folder 4-18)
  - Homeland Maps (3 copies), May 1925 (Box 342)
  - Homeland Maps, Apr. 1927 (Box 342)
  - Homeland Maps, Mar. 1928 (Box 342)
  - Homeland Maps, Sept. 1929 (Box 342)
  - Homeland Maps [Re-subdivision of Blocks 1 to 7], May 1926 (Box 342)
  - Plat of Guilford, July 1927 (Box 342)
  - Plat of Guilford, July 1913 (Box 342)
  - Plat of Guilford (linen), July 1927 (Box 342)
  - Map of Greater Baltimore, Apr. 1919 (Box 342)
  - Published booklet of photographs Forest Hills Gardens Sage Foundation Homes Company, 1913 (Box 342)
- Series III. Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s 1917 correspondence
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr. cc to Sheppard, Baltimore, MD re Roland Park (Box 106, Folder 92)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr. carbon to Geroge J. Roche and Son re Dr. Kelsey's house, Jan. 17, 1917 (Box 107, Folder 466)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s letter and carbon, 1917 (Box 107, Folder 507)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s letter and carbon Kelsey's carbon, 1917 (Box 107, Folder 513)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s carbon letter to Mr. Manning re Ames House, Jan. 9, 1917 (Box 108, Folder 723)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. letter to Arthur West, Jan. 23, 1917 (Box 108, Folder 707)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to J.J. Byrnes, Aug. 2, 1977 (Box 108, Folder 882)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to the Cowan Bldg. Co., Jan. 23, 1917 (Box 108, Folder 917)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to William Shirley, Jan. 2, 1917, Jan. 29, 1917 (Box 108, Folder 927)
  - Edward L. Palmer Jr.'s cc. to Dr. Ronald T. Abercrombie, Jan. 4, 1917 (Box 109)
  - Edward L. Palmer's cc. to Samuel T. Edel, Jan. 11, 1917, Jan. 26, 1917 (Box 109)
  - Edward L. Palmer's ccs. to Mssrs. John Hiltz and Sons Co., Jan. 2, 1917 (Box 110)
  - Edward L. Palmer's ccs. to Mssrs. John Hiltz and Sons Co., Jan. 9, 1917 (Box 110)
  - Edward L. Palmer's ccs. to Mssrs. John Hiltz and Sons Co., Jan. 11, 1917 (Box 110)
  - Edward L. Palmer's ccs. to Mssrs. John Hiltz and Sons Co., Jan. 16, 1917 (Box 110)
  - Edward L. Palmer's ccs. to Mssrs. John Hiltz and Sons Co., Jan. 18, 1917 (Box 110)
  - Edward L. Palmer's ccs. to Mssrs. John Hiltz and Sons Co., Jan. 23, 1917 (Box 110)
  - Edward L. Palmer's ccs. to Mssrs. John Hiltz and Sons Co., Jan. 29, 1917 (Box 110)
  - Edward L. Palmer's ccs. to Mssrs. John Hiltz and Sons Co., Jan. 31, 1917 (Box 110)
  - Edward L. Palmer's ccs. to Mssrs. John Hiltz and Sons Co., Feb.-May 1917 (Box 110)
  - Edward L. Palmer Jr.'s cc. to Dr. Harry E. Kelsey, Jan. 2, 1917 (Box 110)
  - Edward L. Palmer Jr.'s cc. to The Minch and Eisenbray Co., Mar. 3, 1917 (Box 110)